

# ANDRES GARZON

(431) 338-9318 andresgarzon-09@hotmail.com Toronto, ON M8V3H4

#### **SUMMARY**

Internationally trained Engineer, with Canadian credential evaluation and authentication report (WES) with four years of experience in WAN and LAN networks and dedicated software developer with experience in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, object-oriented and user-centered design. Work well with designing, testing, and maintaining software programs. Knowledgeable in all aspects of math, science, engineering, and design. Intrinsically motivated with experience in various programming languages.

#### **SKILLS**

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Java
- Python
- React.js
- jQueryMongoDB

- SQL
- WAN/LAN
- IP/v4
- Time management
- Work ethic
- Effective Communication

### **EXPERIENCE**

Software Developer

Bogota, Cundinamarca

Universidad Colegio Mayor de Cundinamarca/ Nov 2021 to Current

- Coded solutions and unit tests to deliver requirements/stories per defined acceptance criteria and compliance requirements.
- Developed and executed test procedures for software components.
- Generated source code based on Java, pulling from technical knowledge of up-to-date app-development standards.
- Performed research and fact-checking to aid in application planning and creation.
- Designed and built application software with minimal supervision.

Associate-Technology

Windsor, ON

Sutherland/Oct 2021 to Current

- Answers phones and responds to customer requests
- Provide customer with product and service information
- Identify, research and resolve technical customer issues as trained
- Diagnose, troubleshoot and resolve basic to advanced technical concerns.
- Document customer notes, reports and logs.
- Meet client contractual goals and metric wit.

Support Engineer Level 3

Bogotá, Colombia

EZENTIS/Oct 2018 to Aug 2019

- Maintained communication networks, monitored network performance, and resolved any technical issues.
- Installed and configured network devices, including routers, modems, hubs, switches, wireless AP's, and WLAN controllers.

- Worked in the intermediate customer service providing solutions to the problems in the system.
- Evaluated Q&S provided to the customer.
- Provided excellent service and attention to customers when face-to-face or through phone conversations.
- Improved operations by working with team members and customers to find workable solutions.
- Recognized by management for providing exceptional customer service.

**Engineer Specialist** 

Bogota, Cundinamarca

AXESAT/ Oct 2016 to Jun 2018

- Worked in coordination with technicians to support excellence in IT services.
- Completed troubleshooting, tested networks, and performed other duties as required.
- Assessed and assisted customers in different areas and different products of category 3
  of complexity.
- Ascertained and defined user requirements for proposed systems, calculating appropriate hardware components and performance thresholds.
- Monitored and ensured customers connectivity.

**Support Engineer** 

Bogota, Cundinamarca

SOTEC/Jul 2015 to Jun 2016

- Responsible for supporting the high-quality customer service.
- Collaborated with colleagues on the improvement of network infrastructure in order to increase quality, reliability, effectiveness, and reduce expenses.
- Coordinated technicians to provide maintenance in remote devices and warranty optimum service.
- Verified connectivity to all remotes equipment and ensured redundancy, scalability, and security on all networks.
- Documented, repair processes, and helped streamline procedures for future technical support actions.

## **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

Bachelor of Science: Electronic Engineering

Santo Tomas University Apr 2016

Bogotá, Colombia

Specialist: Project Management - Information Technology

Santo Tomás University Jun 2017 Bogotá, Colombia, Colombia

#### **ACTIVITIES AND HONORS**

National champion in math, physics and chemistry. Santo Tomas University. 2011.

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

**Grace Bordon-Buan** 

204-4774601 University of Manitoba Aramark Canada Manager Brodie Centre **Robyn Gabel** 

**Robyn Gabel** 204-9302728

Concordia Hospital

Aramark Canada

Food Service Manager

## **LANGUAGES**

Spanish:	English:
Native/Bilingual	Professional

# WEBSITES, PORTFOLIOS, PROFILES

• linkedin.com/in/andrés-fabián-garzón-sánchez-3b614611b